Tufts Alumni Review UP004
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Tufts Alumni Review
1947 -- 1969
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Tufts University Alumni Association
UP004
12 Volumes
1 Artifact(s)
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of the Tufts alumni magazine from 1947 to 1969 which replaced the Tufts Topics. This magazine was itself replaced in 1969 by the Tufts Criterion.
Volume numbering begins in 1947 with vol. 1, runs through vol. 7 in 1952. The 1953 volume is numbered vol. 53, and 1954 is vol. 54. In 1955 numbering begins with vol. 1 again.
Related Materials
UP003, Tufts Topics, DCA
UP052, Tufts Magazine, DCA
UP053, Tufts Criterion, DCA
UP065, Tufts Review, DCA
- Tufts Alumni Review, 1947 -- 1969; UP004.001; 12 Volumes; 1 Artifact(s)
  Scope and Contents
  Volume numbering begins in 1947 with vol. 1, runs through vol. 7 in 1952. The 1953 volume is numbered vol. 53, and 1954 is vol. 54. In 1955 numbering begins with vol. 1 again. Tufts alumni magazine from 1947 to 1969, replacing the Tufts Topics. This magazine was itself replaced in 1969 by the Tufts Criterion.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1947-03; UP004.001.001.00001 (Box Volume 1)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1947-05; UP004.001.001.00002 (Box Volume 1)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1947-10; UP004.001.001.00003 (Box Volume 1)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1947-12; UP004.001.001.00004 (Box Volume 1)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1948-02; UP004.001.001.00005 (Box Volume 1)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1948-05; UP004.001.001.00006 (Box Volume 1)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1948-10; UP004.001.002.00001 (Box Volume 2)
    [Alumnae association of New York] meeting held May 1, 1948 in Women's club house of Wannamaker's; Lawrence W. Abbott (A1929, R1930, H1948). Honorary Degree Recipient, 1948 (D.D.).
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Winter, 1949; UP004.001.002.00002 (Box Volume 2)
    [Alumni varsity club] Smoker; Alumni day; [Alpha Tau Omega] tablet: In memory of members who gave their lives in World War II [Everett R. Beckman] [Gerlad Silas Bennett] [Walter Mann] [Wilfred Harvey Ringer, Jr.][Includes photos][Tom Mulhoolland, A1951][John Lavelle, A1949]
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Spring, 1949; UP004.001.002.00003 (Box Volume 2)
    [Alpha Tau Omega] Golden Circle Members, William L. Locke [LA1900], Dr. Harry Hersey [LA1903], Silver Circle Members, James F. Folsom [LA1926], Albert R. Folson [1927]
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Fall, 1949; UP004.001.002.00004 (Box Volume 2)
    Alumni day
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Winter, 1950; UP004.001.002.00005 (Box Volume 2)
    Alumni council; Academic Honors, 1949. Recipients (photo): George E. Minot, Jr., Sylvia Hall, Virginia Taylor, Rudolph Fobert. p. 20.
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Spring, 1950; UP004.001.002.00006 (Box Volume 2)
    Mrs. Julia Gibbs Adams (1903). Death of, August 22, 1949.
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Summer, 1950; UP004.001.002.00007 (Box Volume 2)
    Dr. Philip E. Adams (D 1917). Elected Tufts Alumni Council.
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Winter, 1951; UP004.001.003.00001 (Box Volume 3)
    [Abbott, Karl P.] Open for the Season. Book review of, by B. R. H. p. 21.
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Spring, 1951; UP004.001.003.00002 (Box Volume 3)
    Karl P. Abbott (1912). Death of, December 18, 1950.
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Summer, 1951; UP004.001.003.00003 (Box Volume 3)
    [Administration] Administration changes. pp. 11-13; Alumni council; Alumni day photos
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Winter, 1952; UP004.001.003.00004 (Box Volume 3)
    Alumni council
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Spring, 1952; UP004.001.003.00005 (Box Volume 3)
    Vincent J. Alessi (1950) Hero in North Korea.
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Summer, 1952; UP004.001.003.00006 (Box Volume 3)
    Alumni day [includes photo]
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Centennial (1852-1952) Issue, UP004.001.003.00007 (Box Volume 3)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Spring, 1953; UP004.001.004.00001 (Box Volume 4)
    Robert W. Meserve participation in alumni affairs; Death of [Rev. William C. Abbe 1938] Oct. 30, 1952 p. 34; Clara Foster Fraser [J1923] [Alumnae Hall] a dream materializes
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Fall, 1953; UP004.001.004.00002 (Box Volume 4)
    [alumni association] Report to C.B.V.; Alumni council; Alumni day, photos of several groups
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1954-01; UP004.001.004.00003 (Box Volume 4)
    Alumnae Hall [photo]; Alumni council
  - Tufts Alumni Review, [Spring], 1954-05; UP004.001.004.00004 (Box Volume 4)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, [alumni day Pictorial], 1954-07; UP004.001.004.00005 (Box Volume 4)
    Abbott, Donald G. Photo with Miller, Dr. George S. p. 13.
  - Tufts Alumni Review, [Fall], 1954-11; UP004.001.004.00006 (Box Volume 4)
    [Admissions, 1954-55] [Curtis E. Grant] How Tufts Chooses Its Students; Alumnae hall [photo]
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1955-02; UP004.001.005.00001 (Box Volume 5)
    [Admissions] Curtis, Grant E. (A1942) Tufts Admissions, 1854-1954. pp. 8-9.
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1955-05; UP004.001.005.00002 (Box Volume 5)
    Dr. Herbert W. Adams (D 1906). Named Man of the Year in Dentistry by the Massachusetts Dental Society, February 1955.
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1955-07; UP004.001.005.00003 (Box Volume 5)
    [Alumni association] Annual meeting held alumni day; Alumni council
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1955-10; UP004.001.005.00004 (Box Volume 5)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1956-02; UP004.001.005.00005 (Box Volume 5)
    [Alumni council] Classes in art, New alumni handbook; Freeland K. Abbott (A1942, F1947). Pakistan Notebook - A Journey into Time (includes several photos). Academic Convocation (1955). Academic Honors; Tufts Scholar Athletes; p.10.
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1956-05; UP004.001.005.00006 (Box Volume 5)
    John Ahern. Jumbo Jottings.
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1956-07; UP004.001.005.00007 (Box Volume 5)
    [Alumni day] Photos; [Alumnae Hall] Dedicated May 19, 1956 [Includes photo of Ruth Capen Farmer inveiling tablet bearing grandmother's name, Ruth Capen Farmer]; [Aldrich, Henry E.] Honorary Degree Recipient, 1956 (Sc.D.). [Aldrich, Nelson W.] Honorary Degree Recipient, 1956 (L.H.D.).
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1956-10; UP004.001.005.00008 (Box Volume 5)
    [Administration] Administrative appointments, 1956. pp. 3-4.
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1957-02; UP004.001.006.00001 (Box Volume 6)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1957-05; UP004.001.006.00002 (Box Volume 6)
    [Alpha Xi Delta[ Photo taken at 50th anniversary tea of Boston Alumnae chapter, Also of lambda chapter, founded on the Tufts campus in 1907. p13
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1957-07; UP004.001.006.00003 (Box Volume 6)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1957-10; UP004.001.006.00004 (Box Volume 6)
    Alumni council awards presented to George Fee, Helen Gifford, Joan Dartnell, Gerry HIggs [includes photo wtih Dean Miller]
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1958-02; UP004.001.006.00005 (Box Volume 6)
    The Alumni act, calendar of events; Myron S. Allen (E 1923) Reprint of article appearing in the "Independent-Press-Telegram" of Long Beach, Cal., "Brainstorming into Outer Space".
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1958-05; UP004.001.006.00006 (Box Volume 6)
    [Admissions] Reed, Robert G. (A1943) Who Is Getting Into Tufts? (incl. photos). pp. 3-4, 7; [Alumni council] Twenty-fifth anniversary
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1958-07; UP004.001.006.00007 (Box Volume 6)
    Alumni day; Alumni council awards presented to George Fee, Helen Gifford, Joan Dartnell, Gerry HIggs [includes photo wtih Dean Miller]
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1958-10; UP004.001.006.00008 (Box Volume 6)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1959-02; UP004.001.007.00001 (Box Volume 7)
    Richard Adair (1957) married September 17, 1958 to Susan Rolvonen (Simmons) at South Weymouth, Mass. p. 18; [Adler, Roy] Married September 13, 1958 to Sandra Fooks at New Rochelle, N.Y.. p. 18. [Aimetti, Elizabeth] Married October 11, 1958 to Paul Wood, Jr. at Manchester, Connecticut. Nancy Allott (Bouve 1952) Married 1/31/59 to Joseph Moore.
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1959-05; UP004.001.007.00002 (Box Volume 7)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Summer, 1959; UP004.001.007.00003 (Box Volume 7, Box Shared 10)
    Alumni weekend [includes many photographs]; [Alumni council] Awards to seniors
    magazine (periodical); magazine (periodical)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Winter, 1960; UP004.001.007.00004 (Box Volume 7)
    Death of (10/5/59) Kathleen Savage Allison (Staff); Alumni council
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Spring, 1960; UP004.001.007.00005 (Box Volume 7)
    Alumni council; Lester Allen (A1927) Officer in Department of State (incl. photo); Susan Altman [Eliot Pearson 1959] married August 30, 1959 to Stanley Mitnick [E1959] at Neward, N.J.
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Summer, 1960; UP004.001.007.00006 (Box Volume 7)
    Alumni day; [Alumni council]Special program for Alumni returning to campus sessions (SPARC) [includes photos]; [Alumni association] Includes photograph of George S. Miller and Harry C. O'Brien; [Alumni] Reunions, classes over 50 years; [The AlunUS/A prologue] A special supplement prepared by the Aemrican Alumni Council, limited to 1,000 copies and not distributed with all issues
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Fall, 1960; UP004.001.007.00007 (Box Volume 7)
    Death of Benjamin F. Adams (1904), May 22, 1960. p. 46. Death of Herbert W. Adams (D1906), May 8, 1960. p. 49. Staurt Adelman (1960). Married June 16, 1960 to Margot Jasie (Wheaton) at New York City. Richard Allard (d 1964) Married 6/18/60 to Beverly Serrano (Mt. Ida Jr. College) at Billerica, Mass.
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Winter, 1961; UP004.001.008.00001 (Box Volume 8)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Spring, 1961; UP004.001.008.00002 (Box Volume 8)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Summer, 1961; UP004.001.008.00003 (Box Volume 8)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Fall, 1961; UP004.001.008.00004 (Box Volume 8)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Winter, 1962; UP004.001.008.00005 (Box Volume 8)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Spring, 1962; UP004.001.008.00006 (Box Volume 8)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Summer, 1962; UP004.001.008.00007 (Box Volume 8)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Fall, 1962; UP004.001.008.00008 (Box Volume 8)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Winter, 1963; UP004.001.009.00001 (Box Volume 9)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Spring, 1963; UP004.001.009.00002 (Box Volume 9)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Summer, 1963; UP004.001.009.00003 (Box Volume 9)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Fall, 1963; UP004.001.009.00004 (Box Volume 9)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Winter, 1964; UP004.001.009.00005 (Box Volume 9)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Spring, 1964; UP004.001.009.00006 (Box Volume 9)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Summer, 1964; UP004.001.009.00007 (Box Volume 9)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Fall, 1964; UP004.001.009.00008 (Box Volume 9)
    Beatrice Adams (Eliot Pearson 1960) married Richard Miller (Nichols College) July 1964. p. 42
  - Tufts Alumni Review, April, 1965; UP004.001.010.00001 (Box Volume 10)
    [Alumni council] Alumni weekend committee [includes photo]
  - Tufts Alumni Review, June, 1965; UP004.001.010.00002 (Box Volume 10)
    S.H. George Allen Jr. (A1951) Assistant professor of biochemistry at Albany Medical College (incl. photo).
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1965-08; UP004.001.010.00003 (Box Volume 10)
    [Alumni council] Officers and executive committee [photos], Special Program from alumni returning to campus sessions: photo of administrators
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1965-12; UP004.001.010.00004 (Box Volume 10)
    Samuel Adelson (M 1922). Death of, June 30, 1965.; Abbey, Albert A. (M1964) married Joan E. Stein (B.U.) Sept. 1965 in Peekskill, N.Y. p. 54. [Aitken, Patricia Jean] (J 1958) Married July 1965 to Rev. Gilbert E. Dahlberg in Winchester. Jane E. Albee (J 1965) Married september 1965 to Stephen A. Grzenda (A 1964) in East Arlington, Vermont. Constantine Alexander (1963) Married August 1965 to Catherine Stroh (E.P. '63) in Sudbury MA. Death of (5/2/65) Eugene Allen (M 1929); News clippings, Boston Herald (5/3/65), Worcester Telegram (5/3/65), Journal of the Medical Assoc. (Chicago, Ill. 9/6/65). Susan Allen (Bouve 1963) Married September 1965 to Arthur Stukey (1964) in Weymouth.
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1966-03; UP004.001.010.00005 (Box Volume 10)
    Freeland K. Abbott (A1942, F1947, F 1952). Appointed Chairman of Department of History (includes photo); [Aghababian, Robert V.] Married August 1965 to Sandra S. Russian (B.C.) in Watertown, p. 31. Reginald Alleyne (1954) Passed state bar examination in New Mexico, becoming first negro ever licensed to practice law in that state.
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1966-07; UP004.001.010.00006 (Box Volume 10)
    [alumni association] Officers and trustees [includes photos]; Louis Adelson (E 1917). Death of, January 13, 1966. Ainbinder, Martin (A 1957). Married to Dr. Joan Arboit in New York City.
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1966-11; UP004.001.010.00007 (Box Volume 10)
    Lawrence Abrams (A 1959). Married July 1966 to Sylvia Rosenfeld (Victoria School of Nursing, Queen Charlotte Hospital School of Obstetrics, England) in Brookline. [Albert, Samuel M.] (M 1928) Death of, May 15, 1966. Juan Alonso (faculty) The Chipped Wall (book review), p. 29.
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1967-03-01; UP004.001.011.00001 (Box Volume 11)
    Walter L. Abel Jr. (1967). Married October 1966 to Constance A. Littleton in Winchester.
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1967-06; UP004.001.011.00002 (Box Volume 11)
    [Alumni] Five Tufts alumni named Outstanding Young Men by Greater Boston Junior Chamber of Commerce [includes photos]; Henrietta Altman [BSOT1923] died December 22,1966; Jacob Alpers [M1928] Death of, August 12, 1966. Mark F. Acera (A 1964). Married April 1967 to Catherine M. Quartarone in West Roxbury. Alan Alemian (A1964) Named Associate director of Peace Corps in Sierra Leone, West Africa (incl. photo).
  - Tufts Alumni Review, 1967-08; UP004.001.011.00003 (Box Volume 11)
    Alumni day; [Alumni association] Alumni weekend [Includes photos], Officers elected; [Alumni] Top of the hill dinner dance; Lester M. Abelman (A 1943, M 1947). Married June 1967 to Gertrude J. Sell (Smith) in South Hadley.; [Adolph, Joseph F. (M1967)] Married June 1967 to Nancy R. Noss (Wheaton) in Boston. p. 59. [Aisner, Mark] (M 1935) Recieves gavel from Dr, Christopher Duncan (M 1928) as chairman of Medical Dean's Day program (incl. photo). Dorothy Farr Aldrich (J36) Teaches courses in Creative Dramatics for Children (incl. photo). Reginald H. Alleyne Jr. (A54) Recieved 1966 Younger-Federal-Lawyer Award from Federal Bar Association (incl. photo). Myron Allukian (A60) Recieved M.P.H. degree from Harvard, June '67, p. 42.
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Fall, 1967; UP004.001.011.00004 (Box Volume 11)
    Death of Bernard B. Alperstein [M19] March 23, 1967; [Henrietta Alsterlund, Museum 1967] Married September 1967 to Theodore F. Moore in Southboro
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Winter, 1968; UP004.001.011.00005 (Box Volume 11)
    Walter G. Alpaugh [1907] Death of Walter Alpaugh, October 19, 1967; [Alumni] oldtimers hold annual get together
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Spring, 1968; UP004.001.011.00006 (Box Volume 11)
    Clement N. Amaral [D1924] died May 5, 1967; Alumni day; Dorothy Altman [J1964] married in 1968 to Stephen R. Weber; Freeland K. Abbott (A1942, F1947, F1952). Islam and Pakistan - Review of book. Reginald Alleyne (54) Recipient of fellowship awarded by Columbia to lawyers of exceptional achievement.
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Summer, 1968; UP004.001.011.00007 (Box Volume 11)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Fall, 1968; UP004.001.011.00008 (Box Volume 11)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Winter, 1969; UP004.001.012.00001 (Box Volume 12)
    [Alumni council] Alumni leaders symposium
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Spring, 1969; UP004.001.012.00002 (Box Volume 12)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Summer, 1969; UP004.001.012.00003 (Box Volume 12)
  - Tufts Alumni Review, Fall, 1969; UP004.001.012.00004 (Box Volume 12)